Guide to the Cornell University student class printed memorabilia, 1902-1924.
Cornell University student class printed memorabilia
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University student class printed memorabilia, 1902-1924.
37-5-3019
1.1 cubic ft.
Broadsides, ephemera, and other printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Included are announcements, invitations, tickets, programs, menus, dance cards, handbooks, directories, class statistics, schedules, broadsides, dance cards, programs, periodicals, and other printed items relating to class activities.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are announcements, invitations, tickets, programs, menus, dance cards, handbooks, directories, class statistics, schedules, broadsides, dance cards, programs, periodicals, and other printed items relating to class activities such as balls, banquets, Class Day celebrations, Junior and Senior Week events, Spring Day, athletic events, lectures, Masques, smokers, "stunts," and other campus events. Programs, menus, and memorabilia from the Class of 1904, including programs from the 1902 "Stunt"; the Savage Club, 1903; and Junior Week Masque, 1904; and menus from the Class of 1890 Sophomore Banquet, 1888; the Kappa Sigma banquet, 1902; 1903-1905; 1904 Smoker; the 1907 Freshman Banquet; 1906 Class Day program and Freshman Banquet menu/program; 1905 Sophomore Cotillion dance card; 1912 Junior Week Guide; 1914 Senior Ball dance card; 1916 Class Day program; 1922 Junior Smoker 1935 Junior Prom dance card; 1937 Senior Ball dance card; 1939 Spring Day Program; and Senior Week programs from 1922, 1924, and 1925, and many more.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Masque; Cornell Masque.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University; Cornell University. Class of 1890.; Cornell University. Class of 1904.; Cornell University. Class of 1906.; Cornell University. Class of 1907.; Cornell University. Class of 1912.; Cornell University. Class of 1914.; Cornell University. Class of 1916.; Cornell University. Class of 1922.; Cornell University. Class of 1924.; Cornell University. Class of 1935.; Cornell University. Class of 1937.; Cornell University. Class of 1939; Kappa Alpha Society. Cornell Chapter.; Kappa Alpha Society. Cornell Chapter; Savage Club of Ithaca, New York; Savage Club of Ithaca, New York.
Subjects:
Students
Form and Genre Terms:
Programs (documents); Menus.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also Cornell University commencement programs, #37-8-346.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Collection items filed by Class graduating year, not by year of event.
CONTAINER LIST
- Class of 1870 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Assorted Tickets for Lectures
- Class of 1872 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Class Ticket and Class Supper Program
- Class of 1873 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Assorted Tickets for Lectures, Class Tickets, and Junior Exhibition
- Class of 1874 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Assorted Tickets for Lectures, Senior Class Dinner programs
- Class of 1875 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Assorted Tickets for Lectures and Senior Hop
- Class of 1877 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Circus and Senior Class Supper
- Class of 1878 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Assorted Tickets for Lectures and Junior Exhibition,
- Class of 1880 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Sophomore Class Supper
- Class of 1881 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Sophomore Class Banquets, Junior Class Supper, Engineer's Banquet, and Minority Commencement Reception
- Class of 1882 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Sophomore Class Supper, Senior Class Ticket, and Woodford Orations at Library Hall
- Class of 1883 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Freshman Class Supper, Sophomore Class Supper, Sophomore Banquet, Sophomore Class Excursion, Card marking registration for the term, Assorted Tickets for Lectures, Junior Promenade, and Mailing List
- Class of 1884 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Barbecue and Cremation, Physical Measurements and Tests, and Goose Chase
- Class of 1885 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Alphabetical List of Students, Freshman Examination in Gastronomy, Sophomore Banquet, Sophomore Excursion, and Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Dinner
- Class of 1886 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Card marking registration for the term, Freshman Excursion and Banquet, Sophomore Banquet, Junior Promenade, Annual Inspection Tour, Funeral for Al G. Bray, the Woodford Orations, Banquet and Cremation, and Senior Banquet
- Class of 1887 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  List of Students and Field Day
- Class of 1888 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Freshman Excursion and Cremation, Cremation of Tod Hunter and Wells, Freshman Banquet, Banquet and Cremation, Students' Handbook, Beta Delta Chapter Initiation and Banquet, the Junior Promenade, Records of the Class of Eighty-Eight, and Visitors Book
- Class of 1889 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Junior Promenade, Senior Promenade, Woodford Prize in Oratory, and Junior Contest in Declamation
- Class of 1890 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Freshman Banquet, Sophomore-Freshman Excursion and Cremation, Sophomore Banquet, Junior Promenade, Senior Promenade, '90 at Cornell: A Narrative, and Funeral of Al G. Bray
- Class of 1890 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Freshman Minutes, Freshman Banquet, Freshman Class Prayer Meetings, Dues, Sophomore Banquet, Senior Election, Senior Ball, Banquet Songs, Senior Statistics, and 25th Reunion
- Class of 1892 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Sophomore-Freshman Cremation, Burial of Tomahawk, and Banquet, Sophomore Banquet, and Junior Contest in Declamation
- Class of 1893 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Ticket for Lecture
- Class of 1895 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Senior Promenade and Senior Banquet
- Class of 1896 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Freshman Banquet, Second Military Hop, Junior Promenade, and Third Military Hop
- Class of 1897 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Freshman Banquet, Junior Promenade, and Senior Banquet
- Class of 1898 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Sophomore Cotillion and Junior Promenade
- Class of 1899 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Freshman Banquet
- Class of 1900 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Class of 1902 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Alpha Kappa of Kappa Sigma Banquet to Initiates, Sophomore-Freshman Cremation, Burial of Tomahawk, and Banquet, and A Stunt Given by Cornell's Best Fun Makers
- Class of 1903 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Navy Ball, the Savage Club, and the Sophomore Banquet
- Class of 1904 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Sophomore Smoker bag and pamphlet, Stunt, Senior Ball,09 and Senior Play
- Class of 1905 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Representative Ticket and the Masque Play
- Class of 1906 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Freshman Banquet and Senior Ticket
- Class of 1907 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Barnum Outdone, Freshman Banquet, Sophomore Cotillion, Sophomore Smoker, and Junior Smoker
- Class of 1908 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Agricultural Banquet, Junior Smoker, 1908 Men, 1908 Ten Year Book, 1908 Men Deceased since 40th Reunion, Cornell Alumni Fund List of Donors, June 1948 Reunion, and 1908 Men's 40th Reunion
- Class of 1909 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Junior Stunt, and Senior Banquet
- Class of 1910 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Glee, Banjo, and Mandolin Clubs, Senior Banquet, and 1910 Stop! Look! Listen!
- Class of 1911 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Freshman Banquet, Sophomore Smoker, Junior Week Guide, and Senior Ball
- Class of 1912 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Freshman Banquet, Tickets for Musical Performances, and Junior Week Guide
- Class of 1913 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Freshman Handbook, University Orchestra ticket, Directory of Class of 1913, and Memorial Services for Terry Alvah Converse
- Class of 1914 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Freshman Banquet, Junior Prom, Senior Ball, Class of 1914 Directory, and Assorted Tickets for Events
- Class of 1915 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Freshman Banquet, Cornell Athletic Activities, and Class of 1915 Directory
- Class of 1916 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Alumni Luncheon, Class of 1916 Directory, the Annual Cornell University Junior Smoker, Forty-Fifth Anniversary Dinner, Program of 1916 Class Stunt
- Class of 1917 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Freshman Banquet, Archibald Oboler business card, and Red Cross Benefit Concert ticket
- Class of 1918 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Cornell University Minor Sports Athletic Association Itinerary for Columbia-Allentown Basketball Game, Stunt, and Freshman Banquet
- Class of 1919 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Freshman Banquet and Alumni Supper and Smoker/Semi-Centennial Celebration
- Class of 1920 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Musical Clubs event announcement, Freshman Banquet, and Gamma of Phi Sigma Kappa Initiation Banquet
- Class of 1921 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Class of 1922 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Freshman Banquet, the Masque of Cornell University presents "Listen to Me," Junior Week Guide, Junior Smoker, Program for Senior Week, and Convocation for the Recognition of Scholarship
- Class of 1923 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Freshman Banquet, Junior Smoker, Junior Promenade, Track Get-Together
- Class of 1924 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Freshman Banquet, AG. Banquet, Basketball Pennsylvania vs. Cornell ticket, Banquet Honoring the Junior Week Guests by Gamma Chapter of Phi Sigma Kappa, "the Wizard of Oz" playbill, and Junior Smoker
- Class of 1925 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  Freshman Banquet, University Boxing Championships tickets, Sophomore Smoker, Junior Week Guide, and Junior Smoker
- Class of 1926 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Women's Freshman Banquet and Junior Smoker
- Class of 1927 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Class of 1928 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Promenade of the Junior Class
- Class of 1929 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Cornell Class Reunions and Junior Smoker
- Class of 1931 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Junior Smoker
- Class of 1932 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Class of 1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Junior Prom
- Class of 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Senior Ball and Junior Week program
- Class of 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Junior Week program
- Class of 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Third Annual Varsity 'C' Banquet
- Class of 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Junior Week Program
- Class of 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Junior Weekend
- Class of 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Freshman Convocation
- Class of 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Parents Convocation
- Class of 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Class of 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Cornell University Glee Club Senior Week